CHRISTOPHER JOEL

INTERNET ENGINEER · UI ARCHITECT

Ownload PDF

☐ chris@scriptolo.gy

(925) 271-0334

ு github.com/cdata

୬ @robodynamo

in /christopherjoel

Profile

I was born in the information age. For the better part of my life I have been immersed in technology, and I have an experience-hardened understanding of what makes interfaces effective and usable. I make it my business to take the latest web technologies and integrate them into my work.

Emphasis

UI Architecture

I was building multi-touch, mediaheavy UIs from scratch on mobile before it was cool (think Flash Lite on Nokia devices). Little-big details are my obsession.

Web Optimization

Users notice every interaction that takes longer than 100ms to complete. I implement tools, processes and applications around the premise of high responsiveness, my favorite littebig detail.

Interactive Storytelling

Every great software experience is a story that a user felt invited to participate in. Great usability comes from effective interactive storytelling, which is my expertise.

Proficiency

JavaScript
PHP · Python
NodeJS · PhantomJS
Adobe Creative Suite
Windows XP · 7

 $\begin{array}{l} \text{HTML5} \cdot \text{CSS3} \\ \text{C} \cdot \text{C++} \end{array}$

BackboneJS \cdot EmberJS \cdot Etc. GNU / Linux Ubuntu \cdot Debian Google Chrome OS \cdot Android Git · SVN ActionScript

 $jQuery \cdot Modernizr \cdot Etc.$

Apple $OSX \cdot iOS$

Webkit · Gecko · Trident

Experience

CloudFlare

UI / Web Performance Engineer

April 2010 - Present

As the lead front-end engineer at CloudFlare, I am responsible for creating robust and extensible user interface frameworks using JavaScript, Flash and other technologies, to be deployed both internally and across our client sites. I also lead our JavaScript website performance optimization technology development. I am the primary author of CloudFlareJS and Rocket Loader, CloudFlare's JavaScript loading and optimization frameworks, respectively, as well as many other JavaScript libraries deployed across tens of thousands of websites. I am also responsible for establishing CloudFlare's continuous integration process for front-end projects.

IndustryNext User Interface Engineer

October 2009 - February 2010

As a front-end user-interface engineer at IndustryNext, I developed a user interface framework that spanned across Flash Lite, ActionScript 3 and Flex that was deployed across mobile phones, embedded vehicle media systems and desktops.

Garrigan Lyman Group Web Developer

October 2008 - August 2009

As a web developer at The Garrigan Lyman Group, I was responsible for updates to several major product websites for companies such as T-Mobile and Microsoft. The majority of my work is centered around Flash, PHP and .NET development.

IndustryNext Programmer Intern

May 2008 - August 2008

Software developement, using web technologies such as Adobe ActionScript 2 and 3, Flex 3 and JavaScript as well as C++. Developed AS3 / Flex-based skinning engine, plug-ins for Adobe Photoshop CS3, produced a website for a major television network and contributed work to a Flash-based advertising engine. Other responsibilities included design and technical documentation.

Mediaworks Programming & Animation

2004 - 2006

At MediaWorks, I worked as a Flash developer and animator. I applied my knowledge of ActionScript 2.0 to the production of interactive online courses for students taking classes from the University of California. My responsibilities also included redesigning the web site for the parent department of MediaWorks, Information and Education Technology.

Education

Digipen Institute of Technology · Redmond Washington Computer Science, Real-Time Interactive Simulation · Degree Not Completed

© 2012 Chris Joel · chris@scriptolo.gy